

CONTACTS

+359 877 940 083

https://lyubomir-iliev.vercel.app/

https://github.com/lyubomiriliev

www.linkedin.com/in/lyubomiriliev-37ab32305

ABOUT

Birth date: 01.07.1998

Gender: Male

Citizenship: Bulgaria I live in: Sofia, Bulgaria

LANGUAGES

NATIVE LANGUAGE: BULGARIAN

English:

Comprehension (Fluent) Speaking (Fluent) Writing (Fluent)

German:

Comprehension (Beginner) Speaking (Beginner) Writing (Beginner)

Spanish:

Comprehension (Beginner) Speaking (Beginner) Writing (Beginner)

LYUBOMIR ILIEV

Junior Front-end Developer & UI/UX Designer

























PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm a junior front-end developer with two years of work experience, primarily working with JavaScript, TypeScript, React, and Next.js.

I have hands-on experience with **React**, **Redux**, **Node.is**, **Express**, and Next.Js. I have a good understanding of HTTP Requests, REST APIs, and Git/Git Flow, and I've used Docker to containerize a project. I have basic understanding of the concept of CI/CD pipeline.

I have base knowledge of the differences between Git Flow and trunk based development. I understand Agile Manifesto and Scrum methodologies. I have used Jira for ticket management and Confluence for documentation.

I've also worked with **Firebase** and **Supabase** for back-end solutions and used tools like **Postman** and **Regbin** for API testing. I have worked with the following authentication protocols: **OAuth**, and **JWT**.

A great learning experience for me was a full-stack project I built using React, JavaScript, SASS, Node, Express, MongoDB, Cypress and **Docker**. It helped me solidify my understanding of the development workflow, debugging, and best practices.

I'm comfortable working with Windows and Mac, and my daily tools include VSCode, Chrome DevTools, React Developer Tools, Redux Toolkit, Slack, Discord, and ChatGPT.

I have experience with hosting on platforms like **Firebase** and **Vercel**.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UBBSLA | July 2023 - present

IT COMMUNICATION & DISSEMINATION MANAGER

- Developed React Websites (SPA) with responsive design, ensuring high performance and excellent user experience.
- Implemented authentication using Firebase, state management with **Redux** and **Context API**.
- Integrated external APIs using Axios and Fetch to seamlessly retrieve and display dynamic data, enhancing site functionality
- Designed wireframes and **UI in Figma** before coding, focusing on simple, clean and fast-loading websites.
- Utilized TailwindCSS for efficient styling, and deployed applications on Superhosting to ensure scalability and performance.
- Integration with Google Maps API/Stripe payments and Resend for email notifications.



SOFT SKILLS

Willingness to learn new technologies, stay updated with industry trends, and improve skills through self-learning.

Highly motivated and adaptable!

Driving License, category: B

LYUBOMIR ILIEV

Junior Front-end Developer

GRAPHIC DESIGN & UI/UX

FREELANCE | (2018-2023)

- Design brand identity for various Bulgarian companies El Shisha, Vapy, Fitty.
- Design logotypes, web pages, banners, flyers, billboards, social media content, menus, woblers and more.

EDUCATION

SOFTUNI | OCTOBER 2023

React.Js Advanced Course

- · Learned Forms, Validations, Routing
- Learned React Hooks and State Management
- · Learned TailwindCSS, Redux, Firebase, Git
- Passed SOFTUNI React JS 2023 Course with 6.00.

NEW BULGARIAN UNIVERSITY | 2017-2021

Graphic Designer | Level: Professional

Skills accquired:

- · Full branding design
- · Print design
- · Logo design
- · WEB design
- UI/UX design
- Creativity

NPGPTO "M.V. LOMONOSOV" | 2013-2017

High School | Level: Professional

Skills accquired:

- · Cinema, audio and video technician.
- · Cinematography and photography
- Basic technical education